Guide to the Julius Bernstein Papers WAG.116
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Subject Files, 1920-1984
  - Religion in Schools: A Shared Time", 1962-1964 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Rent Strikes, 1964 (Box 23A, Folder 1)
  - Reparations (Germany), 1952 (Box 23A, Folder 2)
  - Reparations (Black), 1969 (Box 23A, Folder 3)
  - Restore Our Alienated Rights (R.O.A.R.), 1976-1978 (Box 23A, Folder 4)
  - Revenue Sharing, 1973-1976 (Box 23A, Folder 5)
  - Rhode Island, 1958-1970 (Box 23A, Folder 6)
  - Rhode Island, AFL-CIO, 1966 (Box 23A, Folder 7)
  - Right-to-Work Laws, 1950-1970 (Box 23A, Folder 8)
  - Right-to-Work Laws: Clippings, 1950-1970 (Box 23A, Folder 9)
  - Right Wing Extremists, 1946-1954 (Box 23A, Folder 10)
  - Right Wing Extremists, 1955-1957 (Box 23A, Folder 11)
  - Right Wing Extremists, 1958-1959 (Box 23A, Folder 12)
  - Right Wing Extremists, 1960-1961 (Box 23A, Folder 13)
  - Right Wing Extremists, 1962-1963 (Box 23A, Folder 14)
  - Right Wing Extremists, 1964 (Box 23A, Folder 15)
  - Right Wing Extremists, 1965 (Box 23A, Folder 16)
  - Right Wing Extremists, 1966-1971, 1978 (Box 23A, Folder 17)
  - Right Wing Extremists: COPE, Right Wing Reports I, 1960-1969 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Right Wing Extremists: COPE, Right Wing Reports II, 1960-1969 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Right Wing Extremists: Opposition to, 1962-1966 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Right Wing Extremists: Reports, 1962-1965 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Right Wing Extremists Pamphlets, 1950-1969 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Right Wing Groups: Group Research, Inc. reports, 1962-1965 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Riots, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Romanian Jews: Conference, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Rosen, Sumner, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Rosenberg Trial I, 1951-1952 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Rosenberg Trial II, undated (Box MSOS006, Folder 2)
  - Route 128: Boston's Road to Segregation, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Roxbury, 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Roxbury Riots, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Rumor Clinic, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Rustin, Bayard, 1960-1975 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Sabbath Observance (Jewish Labor Committee), 1963 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Sacco and Vanzetti, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - SANE (National Committee for Sane Nuclear Policy), 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Schools: Boston, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Schools: Boston, 1964-1968 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Schools: Boston, 1970-1978 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Schools: Boston (Boycott), Jan 1964-Jun 1964 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Schools: Boston (Teacher Incentives), 1967 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Schools: Boston (Desegregation), 1965-1974 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Schools: Boston (Desegregation), 1975-1977 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Schools: Boston (Morgan et al. v. Hennigan et al.), 1972-1975 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Schools: Boston (Morgan et al. v. Hennigan et al.), 1972-1975 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Schools: Boston (USCCR Report), Jan 1975-Jul 1975 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Schools: Boston (USCCR Report), Aug 1975 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Schools: Busing, 1971-1974 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Schools: Busing, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Schools: Busing (Labor Attitudes), 1974-1976 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Schools: Busing (Ted Kennedy), 1974 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Schools: Church-State Issue, 1965-1966 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Schools: Decentralization- Community Control, 1969-1972 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Schools: Desegregation, 1947-1968 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Schools: Desegregation: Religious and Lay Leaders Conference, 1972-1976 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Schools: King Middle School Crisis, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Schools: New York City, 1957-1969 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Schools: Public vs. Private, 1961-1973 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Schools: South, undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Schools: South Boston High School Receivership, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Schultz, Rabbi Benjamin, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Secular Jewishness, 1960-1979 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Security Programs, 1955-1960 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Segregation in Transportation, 1954-1961 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Service Employees International Union, Local 285, undated (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Service Employees International Union, Local 925, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Sex Discrimination (Massachusetts), 1973 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Shanker, Albert, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Shaping Safer Cities, 1970-1972 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Sit-ins, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Sittler Case, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Smith Act Trials, 1952-1962 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Smith, Gerald L. K., 1958-1970 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Smoot, Dan Report, 1958-1967 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Social and Economic Equal Opportunity Council (Massachusetts), undated (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Socialism: Foreign/General, 1955-1964 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Socialism: US/General, 1946-1962 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Socialist Party, undated (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Socialist Party, 1930-1947 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Socialist Party, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Socialist Party, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Socialist Party, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Socialist Party, 1951-1954 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Socialist Party, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Socialist Party, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Socialist Party, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Socialist Party, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Socialist Party, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Socialist Party, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Socialist Party, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Socialist Party, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Socialist Party, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Socialist Party, Jan 1964-Apr 1964 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Socialist Party, May 1964-Jun 1964 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Socialist Party, Jul 1964-Dec 1964 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Socialist Party, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Socialist Party, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Socialist Party, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Socialist Party, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Socialist Party, Jan 1969-Jun 1969 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Socialist Party, Jul 1969-Dec 1969 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Socialist Party, Jan 1970-May 1970 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Socialist Party, Jun 1970-Dec 1970 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Socialist Party, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Socialist Party, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Socialist Party, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Socialist Party: Constitutions, 1960-1979 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Socialist Party: National Minutes, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Socialist Party: National Minutes, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Socialist Party: National Minutes, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Socialist Party: Obituaries, 1920-1969 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Socialist Party: "The Party" Newsletter, 1951-1963 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Socialist Party: Realignment Debate, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Socialist Party: Yankee Radical (Newsletter), 1961-1972 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Socialist Party of Massachusetts, 1941-1968 (Box 27, Folder 2a)
  - Socialist Workers Party (SWP): "Veterans and Labor", 1946, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Council, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Southern States Industrial Council, 1955-1966 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Southern Unions, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1967-1969 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Spanish Civil War, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Spanish-Speaking Population (Reports: Boston and New England), 1969-1971 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Speeches, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - State Employees Dispute (Mass.), 1976 (Box 27, Folder 36a)
  - Stevens Strike, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Student Action Movement (Boston), 1965 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Student Mobilization Committee, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 1a)
  - Student Movement, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), 1963-1966 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Students for a Democratic Society, 1968-1969 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Sunday Laws (Blue Laws), 1958-1963 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Supreme Court: Attacks On, 1958-1961 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Survival Kit, 1974-1976 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Task Force of Religious Leaders on Racism: Audit of Programs, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 7a)
  - Taxes, 1941, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Taxes, 1952-1975 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Tax Rebellion, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Teachers Union, 1955-1969 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Tenant Management Corp., 1974 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Tenant Policy Council, 1968-1972 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Tenant Policy Council Minutes, 1969-1973 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Tenant Rights, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Testimonial Dinner, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Thomas, Norman: 75th Anniversary Dinner/Birthdays, Nov 19, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Trotskyists, 1965-1971 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Turn Toward Peace, 1961-1967 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Unemployment, undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Unemployment (Jewish), 1970 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Union Democracy, 1949, 1952-1959 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Union for Democratic Socialism, 1954-1956 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Union Participation, 1953-1957 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - United Auto Workers (UAW), 1961, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - UAW and Civil Rights, 1948-1967 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - UAW: Massachusetts, 1963, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - United Farm Workers, Jewish Labor Commission Support, 1967, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - United Independent Socialist Party, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - United Nations: Attacks on, 1953-1955 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - United Nations: Zionist Resolution, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - United Nations: Zionist Resolution, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - United Packinghouse Workers of America, 1951-1957 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - United Rubber Workers, 1953-1963 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - United States Commission on Civil Rights, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights, 1974-1975 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Boston Hearings, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Boston Schools, undated (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts Advisory Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts Advisory Committee, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts Advisory Committee, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts Advisory Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts Advisory Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts Advisory Committee, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts Advisory Committee, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts Advisory Committee, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts Advisory Committee: Hearing Transcript I, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Massachusetts Advisory Committee: Hearing Transcript II, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: New Bedford, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Regional Advisory Committee, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Religious and Layperson Conference on Boston Schools, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - US Commission on Civil Rights: Schools Study, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - US Labor Party (Boston), 1972 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - United Steelworkers of America, 1954-1963 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - University of Massachusetts: Huckleberry Finn Controversy, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - University of Massachusetts: Labor Relations Center, undated (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Urban Coalition, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Urban Coalition, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Urban Crisis, 1967-1969 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Urban Growth: Regional Forums, 1977-1978 (Box 30, Folder 1a)
  - Urban League, Boston, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Urban League of Greater Boston, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 2a)
  - Urban Renewal, 1967-1968 (Box 30, Folder 2b)
  - Utilities: Massachusetts, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 2c)
  - Vermont, 1954-1976 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Vermont Freedom Forums, 1953-1968 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Vermont: Labor, Civil Rights Clippings, 1960-1962 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Vermont State Labor Council: Resolutions, 1966-1968 (Box 30, Folder 5a)
  - Vietnam Summer, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Vietnam War, 1960-1969 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Vietnam War, 1970-1974 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Violence, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Violence (Boston), 1976 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Violence: Mayor's Committee, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Vocational Education, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Voice of Women, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Voice of the Ghetto, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 13a)
  - Von Karajan, Herbert: Protest, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Voting, 1957-1960 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Voting: Reappointment, 1965-1967 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Voting Rights, 1958-1965 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Wage Earners Committee, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Walker, Edwin A., 1961-1963 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Wallace, George, 1975-1976, undated (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - War on Poverty, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - War on Poverty, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - War on Poverty, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - War on Poverty, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - War on Poverty/OEO: Lobbying Campaign, 1967-1969 (Box 30, Folder 24a)
  - Warsaw Ghetto Memorials, 1962-1977 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - We, the People, 1966-1967 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Welfare, 1966-1970 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Welfare, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Welfare Coalition, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Welfare Fund: New England contacts, etc., 1977 (Box 30, Folder 29a)
  - Welfare Rights, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - White Citizens Councils, 1955-1964 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - White Ethnicity, 1968-1975 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - White, Kevin, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - Williams, Robert F., 1964 (Box 30, Folder 34)
  - Wiretapping, 1954-1967 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Women: ERA, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Women and Work, 1966-1974 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Women and Work, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Worcester Committee to Combat Intolerance, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Worcester Committee to Combat Intolerance, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Worcester Committee to Combat Intolerance, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Workers' Attitudes to Work, 1973-1974 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Workers Control, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Workers Defense League, 1957-1976 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Workers Education, 1948-1958 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Workfare, 1972-1977 (Box 31, Folder 11a)
  - Workfare (Milwaukee), 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 11b)
  - Workforce, Changes in, 1967-1972 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Working Americans Bicentennial Project, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Workmen's Circle, 1952-1959 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Workmen's Circle, 1960-1979 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Workmen's Circle: Boston, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 15a)
  - Workmen's Circle: Forums, 1972-1977 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Workmen's Circle: Plays and Recitations, undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Workmen's Circle: Public Relations, 1940-1959 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Workmen's Circle: Social Action Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Workshop for Equality: Conference, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 19a)
  - Workshops/Seminars: Materials, 1951-1969 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - World of Sholem Aleichem, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - World Veterans Federation, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - World Veterans Federation, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - World Veterans Federation, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Yiddish Culture, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Young Americans for Freedom, 1961-1967 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Young People's Socialist League (YPSL), 1952 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - YPSL, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - YPSL, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - YPSL, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - YPSL, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - YPSL, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - YPSL, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - YPSL, 1965-1967 (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - YPSL, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - YPSL, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - YPSL, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 37)
  - YPSL, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 37a)
  - Youth Freedom Speakers, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 38)
  - Youth Committee for Peace and Democracy in the Middle East, undated (Box 31, Folder 38a)
  - Youth Institute for Peace in the Middle East, 1971-1977 (Box 31, Folder 39)
  - Youth March for Integrated Schools, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 40)
  - Youth Unemployment, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 41)
  - Zatinsky, Milton: Letter on Socialist History, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 42)
- Series II: Non-Print Materials, 1940s-1973
  - Subseries IIIA: Photographs
    - American Veterans Committee (AVC): 10th Anniversary Convention, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - AVC: Convention, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - AVC: Miscellaneous, 1959 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - AVC: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - AVC: Negatives, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - AVC: Officers (Ernie Pyle Chapter), circa 1947 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - AVC: Rhode Island Chapter, undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - AVC: Sympathy Picket for Integrated Lunch Counters (Woolworths), 1960 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - AVC: United Nations Day, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - AVC: Women, undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Civil Rights Week, 1952-1955 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Combined Jewish Appeal of Greater Boston: Leadership Dinner, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Housing Authority, undated (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Labor Committee (JLC): Labor Day, 1951-1952 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - JLC: Solidarity Rally with Hungarian Freedom Fighters and Jewish Egyptians, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - JLC: Women's Division, Officers, 1956; 1969 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Labor Institute on Human Relations, 1954; 1955 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Massachusetts Veteran, undated (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Panoramic Photograph: 8th National Convention Banquet AVC Sheraton Plaza, Boston, Dec 4, 1954 (Box OS009, Folder 1)
    - Portraits (Includes Julius Bernstein, Norman Thomas, William Silk, Roy Gootenberg), undated (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Rally Against Soviet Influence in Egypt, Jan 1965 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Socialist Party Convention (?), 1954, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Unidentified Meeting, circa 1971 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Unity House, undated (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Subseries IIIB: Artifacts and Ephemera
    - Armbands: American Veterans Commitee, undated (Box 48)
    - Banner: "AVC", undated (Box 46)
    - Banner: "American Veterans of Massachusetts" (With emblem), undated (Box 46)
    - Banner: "Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee", undated (Box 47)
    - Banner: "Welcome Delegates", undated (Box 47)
    - Cartoons, 1971, undated (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - Certificates, 1961-1972 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - Certificates (Oversize), 1961-1972 (Box MSOS006, Folder 3)
    - Civil Rights Fliers, 1954-1959 (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - Clippings, 1952-1970 (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - Conference Folios (Oversize), 1947-1966 (Box MSOS006, Folder 4)
    - Ephemera and Posters (Oversize), undated (Box MSOS006, Folder 5)
    - Greeting Cards, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - Insignia: AVC, undated (Box 48)
    - Insignia: Arbeter Ring (Workmen's Circle), undated (Box 48)
    - Insignia: Young Circle League (Workmen's Circle), 1940 (Box 48)
    - Insignia: United Auto Workers, undated (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous Ephemera, undated (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - Pennants: Workmen's Circle, undated (Box 48)
    - Pennants: Italian Confederation of Workers Trade Unions, undated (Box 48)
    - Pennants: International Confederation of Free Trade Unions, undated (Box 48)
    - Pennants: American Veterans Committee, undated (Box 48)
    - Plaque: Citizens Planning and Housing Association, 1973 (Box 48)
    - Posters (Oversize), undated (Flat-file 1, Drawer 15)
    - Scrapbook I, 1954-1962 (Box 49)
    - Scrapbook II, 1963-1965 (Box 49)
    - Scrapbook III, 1965-1966 (Box 50)
    - Scrapbook IV, 1967-1968 (Box 50)
    - Scrapbook V, 1968-1972 (Box 51)
    - Stickers and Stamps, undated (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - Union Hats, undated (Box 45, Folder 32)
- Series III: Unprocessed Materials, 1938-1977
  - Correspondence, reports, publications, and clippings related to segregated housing, labor unions, and unemployment in Boston and in other areas of Massachusetts. There is also material related to national issues and organizations, such as US-Israeli relations and the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, 1948-1977 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence, reports, publications, and clippings related to segregated housing and schools in Boston and other areas of Massachusetts. There is also material related to the A. Phillip Randolph Freedom Budget and the Jewish Labor Committee., 1949-1977 (Box 33)
  - Correspondence, reports, publications, and clippings related to labor unions and socialist groups; segregation in the Boston school system and the "forced busing" controversy., 1948-1977 (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, reports, publications, and clippings related to the Mattapan Jewish Community Center, the Jewish Labor Committee (Northeast Region), the Massachusetts State Advisory Committee (United States Commission on Civil Rights), the 1973 Massachusetts Senate redistricting, affirmative action, the Massachusetts Commission against Discrimination, proposals for a publically funded power company, gun control, labor and radical politics, consumer advocacy, and segregation in the Boston school system., 1953-1975 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence, reports, publications, and clippings related to poverty, low income housing, the Massachusetts State Advisory Committee (United States Commission on Civil Rights) [SAC], the Jewish Labor Committee, segregation in the Boston school system, and the Jewish Community Council of Metropolitan Boston. There are also transcripts of interviews taken in preparation for the Massachusetts Public Employment Project hearings before SAC, as well as a background report and the schedule for the hearings., 1955-1977 (Box 36)
  - Correspondence, reports, publications, and clippings related to right-wing extremism in the United States, segregation in the Boston school system, the Socialist Party, low-income housing, the Jewish Community Council of Metropolitan Boston, "Black separatism," racial violence in Boston, oversight of the Boston Police Department, the Jewish Labor Committee, the Massachusetts State Advisory Committee (United States Commission on Civil Rights), health care, and labor unions., 1938-1977 (Box 37)